apartheid was not always the way in this country. Black people had gone through
emancipation and reconstruction. And then the Supreme Court said, well,
we're not going to grant Congress the power to protect Black people. And we're not going to
stop states from doing what they need to do to protect their citizens. And so once they decided
that separate but equal was fine, that is when apartheid began in this country. And Black
people who had now experienced a certain level of freedom now had to drink water at different
water fountains. It is the stroke of a pen that will change our lives. We have seen it already.
It was the stroke of a pen that made abortion illegal in a country that many of us have only
known it to be legal in. So when you are thinking about voting and not voting, when you are thinking
about engaging in politics and you say, oh, I just, I don't, I don't want to bother with politics.
It really is dire. And I know there are people who are like, oh, it's not that dire. And we don't
have to really be alarmists. And I think that those people have it wrong. I genuinely do.
And I am somebody who is very gifted at seeing trends.